[Episode 32]
Jinxia Pass is a strategic location.
If it falls, the Beijian cavalry
can advance unhindered.
We'll defend it with our lives.
It must not fall.
Report!
Emergency!
Beijian forces have raided Jinxia Pass.
Beijian's ambition is truly wolfish.
They dared to reroute their main force.
General Di, our army has very few troops left
to defend Jinxia Pass.
His Majesty is stationed a hundred li away.
Light the beacon fires,
and reinforcements will arrive
within four hours at most.
Our forces are vastly outnumbered by Beijian.
I'm afraid we can't last four hours.
We are outnumbered,
so we must attack instead of defend.
Send the order!
Light the beacons and follow me into battle!
Yes!
The beacons warn of a crisis at Jinxia Pass.
- Get my horse!
- Yes!
Today, our army shall crush Jinxia Pass!
- Dream on!
- Kill!
Kill!
Huo An!
[Zhi Li]
Zhi Li, happy birthday.
You've grown another year older,
and I've grown taller than you.
From now on, I can always protect you.
And don't call me
little brother anymore, alright?
[Zhi Li]
Zhi Li, happy birthday.
You asked me my wish.
I want to say, from the day
I entered the Shen Mansion,
my wish has never changed.
I want to tell you
that I like you a lot.
I really do.
Nian,
wait for me.
I have so many things to tell you.
I found this while searching the valleys.
I heard that carrying it brings good luck.
I think you are the one
who needs some good luck.
Zhi Li,
will you marry me?
Do you really not care at all
about what happened?
I don't care at all.
Then do you know the knot in my heart
can't be undone by a simple 'I don't care'?
Zhi Li, now,
do you like me even a little?
You said
this peach wood brings good luck
and protects the wearer.
I want you to come back safely.
Nian.
Soldiers of Ning, hold the line!
Nian!
Nian?
Nian.
Your Majesty,
I
haven't failed my duty.
All soldiers, heed the order!
Slaughter every last Beijian barbarian
and make them pay for our lost soldiers!
Report! Great victory!
Di Nian of Ning and First Prince of Beijian
both died in battle at Jinxia Pass.
Finally, this day has come.
They're dead.
Finally.
Nian.
Your Highness,
I did what I promised you.
Zhongwan has taken the realm
without losing a single soldier.
Yin Qing,
you worked with Nian for three years.
How can you still laugh?
Have you thought about
what Zhi Li must feel right now?
I told you,
I am Shangguan Zhao,
not Yin Qing.
Fine.
Then let's end all this as soon as possible.
My lady, a letter from Qingzhou has arrived.
[General Di died for the country]
Nian.
[Died for the country]
Nian!
I have brought you
the head of Beijian's First Prince.
Thank you
for wiping out the Beijian royals for me.
Today, I am here by order
of Zhongwan's Empress Murong Yao
to take your head.
Shangguan Zhao,
I once let you live,
and I can send you to your doom.
Shangguan Zhao!
Nian's blood debt will be paid in blood!
All soldiers, heed the order!
Stop!
I, Murong Yao,
the last royal blood of Zhongwan,
order all Zhongwan troops
to lay down their weapons!
Your Highness, no!
Yin Qing,
your obsession is restoring the kingdom.
But my obsession
is to let the Zhongwan people
live in peace and prosperity
and no longer be displaced.
Soldiers of Zhongwan,
if war breaks out today,
Zhongwan will be the first to suffer,
and our neighbors
will take advantage and attack.
Do you want to restore our kingdom
or destroy the world?
Ying Gua, your father
killed my father and mother
and destroyed my homeland.
I should hate you to the bone,
yet in the end,
I can't even bring myself to blame you.
Because I know you also don't want
to see the realm in ruin.
You are using your own way
to resolve the years of hatred
between our two nations.
Can we ever be even?
You can't even bring yourself to stab me.
How can I believe what you said?
I know well how hard it is for you.
But rest assured.
No matter what choice you make,
I will support you.
Beijian will sneak attack Xigu Pass
in three days.
The arrows will be poisoned,
causing instant death.
I have never doubted you.
There will no longer be Ning and Zhongwan
on Ning's registers.
This land
belongs to all who dwell in it.
The new policy for Zhongwan is here.
The perpetual servitude law is no more.
From this day forward,
slaves are freed and granted land
and may serve and enlist.
This is the true path
for the Zhongwan people.
Mr. Shangguan,
our survivors have been pardoned.
From now on,
there will be no more Wannu Camp.
Your Highness,
Ning is treacherous and cannot be trusted.
When the Ning cavalry
trampled the Zhongwan capital,
did they show any mercy?
From this day forward...
Your Majesty.
I swear by the blood of the emperor,
in the household registers,
there will only be Ning subjects
and no more distinction
between Zhongwan and Ning.
If I break this oath,
may the realm forsake me.
Meng Ting Hui, I hereby promise
all of Zhongwan's former lands are yours,
and Zhongwan will become
a state within a state.
Your Highness,
Ying Gua only wants to claim you and Zhongwan
and make it look justified.
But what I want to give you
is the entire world
and make you the first empress in history.
Ying Gua,
I will reclaim the lost lands of Zhongwan
with my sword.
We don't need your charity!
Zhongwan soldiers, heed my command!
Kill all the Ning dogs and restore our land!
Mr. Shangguan, stop being so willfully blind.
Yin Qing, give up.
I have waited for so many years
and planned for a lifetime.
Today, even if I am the only one
left of Zhongwan,
I will never give up.
Meng Ting Hui!
Since Your Highness wants
to return to Ning so much,
then I will grant your wish.
Shangguan Zhao!
Your Highness!
Mr. Shangguan!
Miss Meng,
you've killed the greatest sinner of Ning.
Now go back to Ning.
Fire!
No!
Mr. Shangguan!
Forget Shangguan.
Just remember Yin Qing.
Miss Meng,
I see
a rainbow.
Miss Meng.
You are?
I am Yin Qing.
With my years of experience
traveling the world,
roaming all the great mountains,
and having read extensively...
Because you two are naturally beautiful!
What position was I promoted to again?
Judge Yin.
No matter how great the storms in this world,
they will eventually cease one day.
Yin Qing, thank you.
Miss Meng,
as long as I am here,
I will definitely keep you safe.
Shangguan.
Shangguan!
Don't leave.
Don't.
Mr. Shangguan,
I'll accompany you.
Situ Xue.
Meng? Meng, you're awake!
Are you hungry? Do you want to eat something?
Do you want some water?
Here.
You're finally back.
I thought I would never see you again.
The war is over.
Now we can finally spend time together.
I also want to see you
open Bofeng House all over the realm.
Now, the soldiers of Ning
all respect and honor you.
No one will dare doubt your identity anymore.
Zhi Shu and I have reconciled as well.
I think this is the best outcome, isn't it?
Mr. Shen treats you with utmost sincerity.
Seeing you have such a good man by your side
puts my heart at ease.
Isn't it the same for you?
You and His Majesty.
Fu Zhi,
for some reason,
I've been thinking about that old tree
at the Shazhou Women's Academy lately.
I also keep thinking
about apricot skin cakes.
Then I'll make some for you right now.
What's wrong?
This is a military camp.
Where would you get the ingredients?
As long as you want it,
even if it's reaching for the moon,
I will get it for you.
Wait for me.
I will.
Look at what I made this time...
Meng?
[To Your Majesty, from Meng Ting Hui]
Your Majesty,
the realm as a betrothal gift
is your promise,
while offering my remaining years
to the land is my duty
and also my way of loving you.
The dust has settled. I shall take my leave
so as not to let you and me down.
I only worry about Zhi Li and Fu Zhi.
Zhi Li lost Nian, and her heart is broken.
Fu Zhi burns like fire,
and fire can turn on itself.
I hope you and Zhi Shu
will protect them for a lifetime
on my behalf.
This is my last selfish wish.
I'll take away my exhaustion,
leaving behind a vast, clear sky.
This is fulfillment.
May you rule over the four seas,
guard the endless land,
and be a great ruler for all time.
May I always be the Meng Ting Hui
who discussed politics with you
under the lamp in the Censorate.
And may every night thereafter,
when you review memorials,
the candle before your desk always be warm.
[Three years later]
Di An?
Mother.
Di An.
How can you fool around before the throne?
Mom, I'm better than my father.
Then you must first train hard.
Mom, why do you like Father?
Zhi Li.
I don't just like him.
I love him.
But it's too late.
Di An.
Uncle.
Good boy, I'll take you
to the training ground
to see where your father used to train.
Uncle, I want to be a great general
to protect Mother and His Majesty.
Great!
[Bofeng House]
Ms. Yan,
now that the imperial merchant plaque
is hung,
we are the most honored
among all 72 merchant houses of the capital.
This is just the beginning.
I'll open branches of Bofeng House
all over Ning.
I'm going to Xuzhou and Bianzhou
to check on new shop locations.
I'll leave the twelve branches
in the capital to all of you.
Yes.
Ms. Yan!
What great news!
I heard that Mr. Shen
has achieved another great merit,
and he's about to be promoted
to a higher rank.
With such good fortune,
why are you bothering with branches?
It's precisely because
they are all in the clouds
that I need to pave the roads
on the ground more extensively.
Let's go.
We see you off, Ms. Yan.
- Safe journey!
- Good luck!
Congratulations.
Have a smooth journey.
Above, a wise ruler bestows his grace.
Below, virtuous ministers give their all.
Only then can the land be governed.
The people nurtured.
And peace secured.
If I can help the people with my life,
[Shazhou Women's Academy]
I will not spare it.
You disguised yourself as Situ Xue
to deceive the people
and concealed weapons with malicious intent.
By law, you should be exiled.
On what grounds do you say I'm fake?
You are selfish and full of lies.
After being exposed, you try to argue.
You're good at playing innocent and pitiful.
You're so cunning, deceitful,
and duplicitous.
How do I know you are not deceiving me?
You really have a deep impression of me.
We meet again,
Miss Meng.
With your power and influence,
instead of going
after the Heihu Crew and Ding Chong,
you waste your time on a helpless woman.
Some ability that is.
If you deceive me, you'll be dead.
Since I brought you in,
I won't let anything happen to you.
A master like you is afraid of a small snake?
At least treat me to a meal first.
Miss Meng,
until we meet again.
If fate allows, we will meet again.
I think He Du in Shazhou
was more interesting than Your Majesty.
Mr. He, warm soup is good for the stomach.
Is the lamb soup good?
Good, very good.
It's just like the one in Shazhou.
Spicy and fierce.
You walked step by step right up to me.
The boy.
He Du.
The emperor.
Over ten years, you have witnessed my life
under different identities.
Why wait for snow to make a wish?
I can fulfill your wishes.
I also hope the Ning Empire
will be peaceful and prosperous.
I hope that next year,
I will still have old friends by my side.
When spring comes,
shall we release floating lanterns together?
It's a promise.
Your Majesty!
Meng Ting Hui,
let's get married.
[Censorate]
Three years have passed.
The Ning Empire misses you.
Now, the storms in the court
have not yet ceased.
Will you walk with me again?